<?xml version="1.0"?>
<info xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="https://apps.nextcloud.com/schema/apps/info.xsd">

    <id>starrate</id>
    <name>StarRate</name>
    <summary>Lightroom-style photo rating for Nextcloud — stars, color labels, XMP metadata, guest links</summary>

    <description lang="en"><![CDATA[
StarRate is a professional photo rating and culling tool for photographers, seamlessly integrated into Nextcloud.

Rate photos with 1–5 stars and color labels, flag picks and rejects with keyboard shortcuts, and share a guest gallery link with your client or model. They pick their favorites in the browser — no Nextcloud account required. Leave comments on individual images for feedback rounds, and export the final rating list as CSV when you're done.

**Ratings are written as XMP metadata directly into the JPEG file.** Open it in Lightroom Classic, digiKam, F-Stop or Darktable — the stars are already there. No re-export, no sidecar files. **Coming from Lightroom?** Import your existing XMP ratings with one `occ` command — your years of curation travel with you.

**Features:**
- Star ratings (0–5) + color labels (Red/Yellow/Green/Blue/Purple) + Pick/Reject flags
- XMP metadata written into JPEG — compatible with Lightroom Classic, digiKam, F-Stop, Darktable
- Import existing XMP ratings from Lightroom/digiKam via `occ starrate:import-xmp` (with `--recursive` for whole folder trees)
- Comments on individual images — for client feedback rounds or personal notes, optional in guest galleries
- Export the rating list as CSV (filename, stars, color, pick/reject) — download or copy to clipboard
- Guest share links for clients and models (no Nextcloud login required), with optional password, expiry, and export permission
- Keyboard shortcuts like Lightroom: 0–5 stars, 6–9 colors, P/X pick/reject
- Batch rating and batch pick/reject with Shift+click / Ctrl+click / Ctrl+A
- Combinable filters: stars, color, Pick/Reject, unrated
- Full-screen loupe view with zoom up to 400%, pan, pinch-to-zoom
- Dark professional UI theme optimized for photo work
- English and German
    ]]></description>

    <description lang="de"><![CDATA[
StarRate ist ein professionelles Foto-Bewertungs- und Auswahlwerkzeug für Fotografen, nahtlos in Nextcloud integriert.

Bilder mit 1–5 Sternen und Farb-Labels bewerten, Picks und Rejects per Tastaturkürzel markieren, und einen Gast-Link an Kunden oder Models schicken. Die wählen ihre Favoriten im Browser — ohne Nextcloud-Account. Kommentare zu einzelnen Bildern für Feedback-Runden hinterlassen, und die fertige Bewertungsliste am Ende als CSV exportieren.

**Bewertungen werden als XMP-Metadaten direkt in die JPEG-Datei geschrieben.** In Lightroom Classic, digiKam, F-Stop oder Darktable öffnen — die Sterne sind schon da. Kein Re-Export, keine Sidecar-Dateien. **Umstieg von Lightroom?** Bestehende XMP-Bewertungen mit einem `occ`-Befehl importieren — deine Jahre an Kuratierung wandern mit.

**Features:**
- Sternbewertungen (0–5) + Farb-Labels (Rot/Gelb/Grün/Blau/Lila) + Pick/Reject-Flags
- XMP-Metadaten ins JPEG geschrieben — kompatibel mit Lightroom Classic, digiKam, F-Stop, Darktable
- Import bestehender XMP-Bewertungen aus Lightroom/digiKam via `occ starrate:import-xmp` (mit `--recursive` für ganze Ordnerbäume)
- Kommentare zu einzelnen Bildern — für Kundenfeedback oder persönliche Notizen, optional in Gast-Galerien
- Bewertungsliste als CSV exportieren (Dateiname, Sterne, Farbe, Pick/Reject) — herunterladen oder in die Zwischenablage
- Gast-Links für Kunden und Models (kein Nextcloud-Login nötig), mit optionalem Passwort, Ablaufdatum und Export-Erlaubnis
- Tastaturkürzel wie Lightroom: 0–5 Sterne, 6–9 Farben, P/X Pick/Reject
- Batch-Bewertung und Batch Pick/Reject mit Shift+Klick / Strg+Klick / Strg+A
- Kombinierbare Filter: Sterne, Farbe, Pick/Reject, unbewertet
- Loupe-Ansicht mit Zoom bis 400 %, Pan, Pinch-to-Zoom
- Dunkles, professionelles UI-Theme optimiert für Fotoarbeit
- Englisch und Deutsch
    ]]></description>

    <version>1.3.1</version>
    <licence>agpl</licence>

    <author mail="starrate@merlin1.de" homepage="https://github.com/merlin1de/starrate">
        Mathias Mischler
    </author>

    <namespace>StarRate</namespace>

    <category>multimedia</category>
    <category>files</category>

    <website>https://github.com/merlin1de/starrate</website>
    <bugs>https://github.com/merlin1de/starrate/issues</bugs>
    <repository type="git">https://github.com/merlin1de/starrate</repository>

    <screenshot>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/merlin1de/starrate/master/screenshots/starrate-grid.jpg</screenshot>
    <screenshot>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/merlin1de/starrate/master/screenshots/starrate-loupe.jpg</screenshot>
    <screenshot>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/merlin1de/starrate/master/screenshots/starrate-share.jpg</screenshot>
    <screenshot>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/merlin1de/starrate/master/screenshots/starrate-newshare.jpg</screenshot>
    <screenshot>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/merlin1de/starrate/master/screenshots/starrate-guest.jpg</screenshot>

    <dependencies>
        <php min-version="8.1" max-version="8.4"/>
        <database>sqlite</database>
        <database>mysql</database>
        <database>pgsql</database>
        <nextcloud min-version="29" max-version="34"/>
    </dependencies>

    <navigations>
        <navigation>
            <name>StarRate</name>
            <route>starrate.gallery.index</route>
            <icon>app.svg</icon>
            <order>10</order>
        </navigation>
    </navigations>

    <commands>
        <command>OCA\StarRate\Command\ImportXmpCommand</command>
    </commands>

    <settings>
        <personal-section>OCA\StarRate\Settings\PersonalSection</personal-section>
        <personal>OCA\StarRate\Settings\UserSettings</personal>
    </settings>

</info>
